A Guide to the Ruth McEnery Stuart Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8790
Ruth McEnery Stuart Collection 1896-1908
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8790
17 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Colletion is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1967 Oct 4 ] 1968 Jan 25
Item Listing
- Letter
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1896 Apr 30; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses an article about New Orleans which she promised him by May 1; says it will be delayed due to problems with photographs.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1896 Jun 3; ALS, 3 p.
    [Sends him article on New Orleans Creoles with photographs; instructs him on how much to pay the woman photographer and to give credit in publication of photographs to "Washburn" who took the pictures of the three beauties; states that her fee is $200.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1896 Jul 11; ALS, 3 p.
    [Acknowledges check; hopes he is pleased with the article; says she is willing to make corrections if necessary and would like to have the proofs; requests proof of his planned article on her life; suggests future article on the Acadians, "Cajuns," of Louisiana. ]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1896 Jul 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Sends him just finished humorous sketch; asks to be sent proofs for correction, if he likes it; gives her new address.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1897 Jul 9; TLS, 1 p.
    [Offers a humorous Christmas story which exceeds the five thousand word limit a little; asks for a quick decision; intends to offer it to another editor in time for Christmas should Bok reject it.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1897 Jul 13; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says she is pleased at acceptance of the manuscript, but expected $300 for it and is sure a mistake has been made; promises more work for him in the future.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1898 Mar 14; ALS, 2 p.
    [Says the Christmas story will be included in a collection of short stories to be published by Harper's; asks permission to use Bok's illustrations; promises to send him a manuscript soon.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1901 Apr 6; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says that her sister, Sarah McEnery, is living temporarily in Holland, plans to write a series of articles on Holland towns, picture galleries, etc. for publication; attempts to get Bok interested in the series; sends him a sample and the asking price; reports on her improving health.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1901 Sep 5; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses corrections of her manuscript "
    If I had a Million
    "; says she has another idea for a Christmas piece, if it is not too late.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1903 Jan 28; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says she is late in answering due to illness; considers his Christmas suggestion.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1903 Apr 30; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says she is still in ill health; encloses a manuscript with permission to do "whatever" with it; requests proofs.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1903 Dec 13; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says she has moved to Long Island, which interrupted completion of a Christmas story; says she will keep him in mind for the future.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1904 May 11; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says she has been overwhelmed by moving and the accumulation of work; promises to send him a piece by July.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1904 Aug 19; ALS, 3 p.
    [Sends promised manuscript of a Christmas story at 6 cents per word; asks for immediate return if he is not pleased.]
  - Ruth McEnery Stuart to Edward W. Bok, 1908 Dec 15; ALS, 2 p.
    [Expresses holiday greetings; says she is working on a few stories about New Orleans and its plantation environs, where she spent time taking notes and sketching.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Obituary of Ruth McEnery Stuart, [1917 May 2]; Clipping
    [Includes biographical sketch which emphasizes that she was a friend of the "blacks."]